layar.com 2010-08-05

# Layar Privacy Policy

### Layar Privacy Policy

  1. #### GENERAL

At Layar we understand that privacy is an important issue and that personal data should be processed in accordance with the applicable legislation. The information provided in this privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") is designed to help you, understand what information we collect, and how we handle the information once we collected it.

If you are an end-user (an "End User") of the Layar websites (the "Layar Websites") or Layar's augmented reality browser (the "Layar Reality Browser") we will collect your data by means of the Layar Websites, through the Layar Reality Browser or through other contacts between you and Layar. If you are a developer (a "Developer") or a publisher (a "Publisher") of third party content and functionalities (the "Content"), we will also collect your data by means of the information, tools, applications, services, products, software, websites and systems (the "Platform") which Layar provides for the purpose of enabling you to create Content as well as the marketing and distribution of the Content, or through other contacts between you and Layar. Providing your personal data through these channels implies knowledge and acceptance of this Privacy Policy.

Layar is the provider of the Layar Websites, the Layar Reality Browser and the Platform. In this respect Layar would like to point out that:

    * when you, as an End User, use the Layar Websites or the Layar Reality Browser, we will process your data necessary for your access to and the subsequent transmission of Content. Layar is the controller with regard to these processings. Please be aware that the Content which you can access by means of the Layar Reality Browser, is provided to you by the Publishers. Layar merely provides the underlying infrastructure for your access to the Content. If you choose to disclose your data with Publishers, these Publishers are the controllers with regard to the processing of your personal data in connection with your use of the Content. The Publishers are independently responsible for compliance with applicable data protection legislation with regard to these processings; Layar does not process or store this data; and
    * when you, as a Developer or Publisher, use the Platform, we will process your data necessary for the marketing and distribution of the Content. Layar is the controller with regard to these processings.

  1. #### COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL DATA

We may use the collected personal data for the following purposes:

    * The provision of access to and subsequent transmission of Content;
    * Improvement and technical administration of the Layar Websites, Layar Reality Browser, the Platform and/or services; and
    * Enabling you to create Content as well as the marketing and distribution of the Content.

Layar only processes those personal data necessary for the fulfilment of the abovementioned purposes. We may collect the following categories of data from you as an End User, namely contact information, device information, profile information, payment information, marketing information, sales information, user generated information, social information and support information. If you are a Developer or a Publisher, we may, in addition to the aforementioned data, also collect content ownership information.

Your personal data will not be sold to third parties.

As part of the services offered to you, the information you provide to us may be transferred to countries within and outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA"). More specifically your personal data may be transferred to hosting parties, email service providers, CRM providers and payment service providers in the United States, having a different level of data protection. However, if we transfer your information outside of the EEA in this way, we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your privacy rights remain protected. The purpose of the transfer is the provision of access to and subsequent transmission of mobile services, including (personalised) augmented reality services.

Specifically to End Users we point out the following:

    * We will also process location data including but not limited to your GPS-location, which we receive from GPS location service providers. These location data shall only be processed for as long as this is necessary for delivering our services or to the extent required or permitted by applicable law.
    * As mentioned above your personal data will not be sold to third parties. However, please note that we will need to disclose personal data such as location data to the Publishers of the Content, since this is necessary to be able to provide you with access to the Content. Furthermore, your personal data may be disclosed to (insert recipient) for the purpose of the delivery of mobile services to you.
    * We may transfer the abovementioned location data to Publishers who may be located in countries outside of the EEA having a different level of data protection for the purpose of providing you with access to the Content. For such transfers we will ask your unambiguous consent.

  1. #### OTHER DISCLOSURES

We reserve the right to access and disclose individually identifiable information to comply with applicable laws and lawful government requests, to operate our systems properly or to protect itself or its users.

We may also disclose your personal data to third parties in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets. We reserve the right to disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets. If Layar or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, personal data about you as a customer will be one of the transferred assets.

  1. #### SECURITY OF THE PROCESSING

We will only process your personal data when appropriate. This means that we will take care that the personal data will only be processed in an accurate and adequate way. We have implemented security measures pertaining to the storage and provision of personal data, in order to, amongst others, prevent access to your personal data by any unauthorised persons.

Please note that your personal data shall only be accessed by authorised staff. These staff members are obliged to preserve the confidentiality of all the information that comes to their attention, unless disclosure is compulsory by law or necessary for the fulfilment of their task.

  1. #### YOUR RIGHTS

You can request to access your personal data and you can verify/correct their accuracy. You can also request the removal of your personal data. Upon your request and verification of your identity, we will rectify, erase or block your personal data, if these data are incorrect or if you no longer want us to process these data. Due to the requested removal, it is however possible that we cannot ensure the provision of (part of) our services.

  1. #### COOKIES

The Layar Websites, the Layar Browser and the Platform use cookies. A cookie is a file that the server sends to your browser and that is stored afterwards on your computer. Cookies are only used for the performance or the facilitation of the performance of a service requested by you. Most of the cookies only function during one session or visit. You can configure your browser in such a way that it will warn you each time a cookie is installed or each time it refuses to install one. Should you refuse the installation of cookies, we cannot ensure the transmission of communications and the delivery of certain services.

  1. #### MODIFICATIONS

We reserve all rights to change this Privacy Policy at any time. All changes will be in conformity with any applicable privacy law. We therefore recommend you to check [www.layar.com/legal](http://www.layar.com/legal) regularly for an update of our Privacy Policy.

  1. #### CONTACT

Should you have any questions concerning our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@layar.com](mailto:privacy@layar.com) or by regular post at:

Layar B.V.

Attn. legal

Rietlandpark 301, 1019 DW Amsterdam, The Netherlands

***
